what is a deductible and why is it so
important
a deductible is the amount of money you
are responsible for paying before the
insurance company starts paying for any
covered expenses
your responsibility does not mean that
you have to pay in cash or up front but
it will be adjusted in your claims and
you will ultimately be responsible to
settle it accordingly
how deductible affects your insurance
cost
it is important to pay attention to what
deductible you choose at the time of
purchasing the insurance policy
as higher the deductible lower the
premium or insurance cost and vice versa
depending on what kind of policy you are
buying you should pick up the deductible
accordingly to keep your out-of-pocket
expenses less you may want to pick a
lower deductible
what is a deductible per incident
insurance policies where the deductible
is applicable per incident you will be
required to satisfy the deductible for
each incident
let's look at an example
let's say you fall ill and need to visit
the doctor
the doctor may ask you to get an x-ray a
blood test and prescribe you some
medications
all of these things are related to your
one illness so therefore considered one
incident and hence deductible will be
applicable only one time for all medical
bills pertaining to this incident
for any new and future medical
situations deductible will be applicable
again what deductible to choose for a
policy with a deductible per incident
since the deductible is per incident
it's a good idea to consider selecting
the lowest deductible
is an annual deductible or deductible
per policy period and why is it
important
insurance policy where deductible is
paid annually or per policy period
a deductible is applicable only once per
year
let's say you purchase a plan with a two
hundred and fifty dollar deductible an
incur total of fifteen hundred dollars
in expenses
the insurance company will begin to
reimburse expenses as per the policy
minus the deductible on the policy for
these types of policies you only need to
pay the deductible once per year no
matter how many medical services you
have used during the year
what deductible should you choose from
where the deductible is annual or per
policy period to keep the insurance
price low choose a high deductible
to keep your liability or out of pocket
limit low choose a low deductible
the choice also depends on your comfort
level
choose the right deductible based on
what amount you could be ready to pay as
deductible should you use the insurance